Titus Evans

Web Developer - Technical Animator - Gameplay Mechanic - Indie Game Developer

snavesutit@gmail.com
github.com/SnaveSutit

INTRODUCTION

Animator with 2+ years of professional experience, seeking to take career to the next level. Enjoys working with a team, while capable of being independent and self-motivated. Key strengths lie in high technical aptitude, problem solving, interpersonal and communication skills. Interested in expanding personal toolbox and learning new skills. Not afraid of being outside the comfort zone.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

• Co-authored two majorly successful open source projects:

<u>Animated Java</u> - A Blockbench plugin designed to streamline and simplify the process of animating complex models in Minecraft: Java Edition.

<u>MCBuild</u> - A pre-compiler for Minecraft: Java edition that streamlines Data Pack development; provides numerous quality of life features missing from vanilla functions.

- Performed Youtube commissions for Bahri and Socksfor1:
 - Created models, data packs, resource packs, textures, and maps to match descriptions provided. <u>Video playlist link</u>
- Owned and maintained a Minecraft: Java edition server over the course of 6 years, developing all of the back-end technology personally and managing its forums and discord guild.

SKILLS

Professional Skills

- Design and maintenance of project task boards.
- Documentation and written communication.
- Lead and management of small teams.
- Working efficiently with teams large and small.

Animation Skills

- Design and implementation of procedural animation that reacts fluidly to a game environment.
- Design and implementation of keyframe animation that merges seamlessly with a game environment.
- Rigged and configured models in preparation for animation.

General Technical Skills

- Development of APIs
- Programming language tokenization and parsing.
- Quick & Clean tool prototyping and development.
- Multithreading and asynchronous code.

Specific Technical Skills

- JavaScript/TypeScript
 - Node.js, VSCode Extensions, Webpack, ESBuild, Svelte, SvelteKit, Promises
- VSCode
 - Extension development, Expansive knowledge of features and keybindings.
- Godot Game Engine
 - GDScript
- Blockbench
 - o Animation, Modeling, Plugin development
- Pvthon
 - o PILLOW, Numpy, Tkinter, discord.py, Flask
- Molang
- HTML/CSS
- Minecraft: Java edition Data/Resource packs
- Minecraft: Bedrock edition Behavior packs
- Lua
- Powershell
- Bash

EXPERIENCE

Moonsworth / Pet Animator & Modeler

JUN 2022 - PRESENT, REMOTE

- Designed and animated models
- Maintained detailed documentation of the animation and modeling pipeline.
- Maintained product quality by analyzing feedback, managing integration and performing continual tests.
- Contributed to code reviews, debugging and optimization.
- Integrated advanced technologies and tools to improve workflow.

- Maintained detailed documentation of software development processes and updates.
- Contributed to code reviews, debugging and optimization.
- Integrated advanced technologies and tools to improve software performance.
- Employed best practices in software development to complete high-quality applications in line with scheduled targets.
- Worked with quality assurance staff to identify issues, validate code and debug issues.
- Maintained product quality by analyzing feedback, managing integration and performing continual tests.
- Utilized industry-accepted testing methods to troubleshoot flaws, including security, acceptance and performance testing.

Coretek / IT Intern

MAY 2018 - JAN 2019, FARMINGTON HILLS, MI

- Assisted with installation and upgrading of software to meet changing team needs.
- Researched technical issues thoroughly to complete accurate repair work.
- Shadowed qualified technical team members to develop maintenance and repair skills.
- Answered telephone calls to assist computer users encountering problems.
- Validated and improved efficiencies of current systems by implementing algorithms..

Providence WorldWide / MIG Welder

SEP 2017 - MAY 2018, WESTLAND, MI

- Analyzed technical drawings, blueprints, specifications and work orders to plan project execution.
- Prioritized tasks according to established schedules, shop orders and established procedures.
- Fit, aligned and adjusted machines and assemblies to meet tolerances and product operating requirements.
- Estimated the materials needed for each job and kept supplies within optimal levels.
- Welded separately or in combination using aluminum, stainless steel, cast iron and other alloys.

EDUCATION

Mountain Heights Academy / High School Diploma

JUN 2018, PLYMOUTH MI